字幕来源：网络
豆瓣@LoudCrazyHeart
后期：Lee.
我发现那个杀人犯
I got the Strangler.
在华比和范拜仁
Wabash and Van Buren.
啊  混蛋
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
杰克  去范那边
Jack, get the van.
艾迪  救我
Eddie, help me!
艾迪  别丢下我  天啊  不
Eddie, Eddie, don't leave me! God, no!
投降吧  雷  结束了
Give it up, Ray. It's over.
鬼娃回魂
天  我要死了
Oh, God, I'm dying.
听到了没  你这个杂种
You hear this, you son of a bitch?
我会那样对你
I'm gonna get you for it!
我会抓住你
I'm gonna get you,
我会抓住艾迪
and I'm gonna get Eddie,
无论如何
no matter what!
我要找个人
I gotta find somebody.
我不知道  但我要找个人
I don't know. I gotta find somebody.
我要找个人
Gotta find somebody.
给我力量吧  求你
Give me the power, I beg of you!
我没有朋友  没有人会和我一起玩
I have no friends. No one will play with me.
啊噢
Uh-oh.
我需要一个朋友
There's a friend in need.
嘿  振作点
Hey, cheer up.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是一个公仔
I'm a Good Guy.
我刚刚从公仔俱乐部来
I've just come from the Good Guy Clubhouse,
我永远都会是你的朋友
and I'll be your friend to the end.
会吗  你意思是你现在也已是我朋友了
You will? You mean you'll be my friend now?
当然是了
Sure, I will.
嗨
Hidey-ho.
我看到这个了
I saw this one.
好了  公仔们
All right, good guys,
这就是我们今天的公仔秀
that's our Good Guys show for today,
但别离开
but don't go away,
因为我们有很重要的公仔信息给大家
because we've got a very important Good Guy message just for you.
嗨  公仔们  孩子  我有一些新闻
Hi, Good Guys. Boy, have I got news for you.
现在你可以拥有自己的公仔了
Now you can have your very own Good Guy doll.
是的
That's right.
你可以在自家的电视里体验所有的冒险经历
You can have all the adventures we have on TV in your very own home.
公仔们  说三句不同的话
Good Guys say three different sentences.
在你跟我们说话时  我们甚至会闭上眼睛和转过头
We even turn our heads and blink our eyes when you talk to us.
对吧  奥斯卡
Right, Oscar?
嗨  我是奥斯卡  我会是你永远的朋友  嗨
Hi, I'm Oscar, and I'm your friend to the end. Hidey-ho.
哇
Wow!
每个公仔都有他自己的名字
Every Good Guy has a name all his own,
这样他才能成为你最好的朋友
so he can be your very own best friend.
所以要记得跟你爸妈说你要一个公仔
So remember to tell Mom and Dad you want a Good Guy.
最好在你生日或任何节日的时候
Perfect for birthdays or just any old time.
记住  你还可以买任何公仔附件
And remember, you can buy all of our Good Guy accessories, too.
-是吧  奥斯卡  -是的
-Right, Oscar? -Right.
如此独一无二的经历由"好玩伴"带来
Brought to you exclusively by Play Pals,
他是公仔还有其它好玩具的制作人
makers of Good Guys and other fine toys.
在芝加哥范围内的玩具店来买吧
Found in toy stores throughout the greater Chicago area.
妈咪  起床
Mommy, wake up.
妈咪
Mommy.
妈咪  起床
Mommy, wake up.
-起床  妈咪  起床  -安迪
-Wake up, Mommy. Wake up. -Andy.
几点了  安迪
What time is it, Andy?
起床
Wake up.
6:30  现在才是早上6:30
6:30. It's only 6:30 in the morning.
但今天外面天气很好  看到了没
But it's a beautiful day outside. See?
当然了
lt certainly is.
你起来多久了  小寿星
How long you been up, birthday boy?
很久了
Since forever.
我在床上就已帮你弄好早餐了
I made you breakfast in bed.
你做的  噢  天啊
You did? Oh, God.
好棒  谢谢
Well, thanks.
啊  它看起来很美味
Well, this looks just excellent.
噢  我会告诉你那是什么的
Oh, I'll tell you what.
我迟一点再吃这些东西  好吗
Why don't I eat this just a little later, okay?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
首先  我先给你一个超级生日礼物
But first, I gotta give you your super-duper, birthday tummy-gummy.
过来这边  过来这边  过来这边
Come here. Come here. Come here.
-就是它  你今年多大了  -两岁
-That's one. How many years old are you today? -Two.
生日快乐  小不点
Happy birthday, pumpkin.
谢谢  我现在可以打开我的礼物吗  妈妈
Thanks. Can we open my presents now, Mommy?
是的  可以
Yes, we can.
好极了
Terrific!
早上好  芝加哥  现在开始播报
Good morning, Chicago. Leading off at this hour,
查尔斯·李·雷  声名狼籍的杀人犯
Charles Lee Ray, the notorious Lake Shore Strangler was shot and killed
今天早上3点前在华比街被枪杀
shortly before 3:00 a.m. this morning on Wabash Avenue.
我可以先打开他吗  妈咪
Can I open this first, Mommy?
我可以吗  我可以吗
Can I, can I?
安迪  你为什么不先看那个小一点的呢
Andy, don't you want to start with the smaller one first?
好的  继续
Okay, go ahead.
好吧  觉得怎么样  你很需要这些衣服
Well, what do you think? You need these clothes so badly.
我想它们还好啦
Hey, I think they're gonna be okay.
我们只需剪去几英寸
We'll just have to take them up just a couple of inches.
怎么啦
What's the matter?
没什么
Nothing.
我知道了  你想要一些玩具  是吧
Oh, I know. You want some toys, don't you?
而不是讨人厌的破旧衣服
Not boring old clothes.
试试这个吧
Try the other one.
怎么样
Well, what do you think?
我想要一个配套的公仔
I want a Good Guy to go with it.
我了解  安迪
I know you do, Andy.
但这个月因为事先不知道就没来得及凑钱
But I didn't know about it in time this month to save up for it.
-凯伦  -嗨
-Karen. -Hi.
你知道你想买给安迪的那个公仔吧
You know that doll that you wanted for Andy?
-100块的那个  -是的  公仔
-The one that costs 100 bucks? -Yeah, the Good Guy doll.
这商店后面有一个小贩
There is a peddler in the alley behind the store,
我想他可能有那玩意
and I think he's got one.
什么  为什么小贩会有
What? What would a peddler be doing with a doll?
管那么多干什么  你买不买  我觉得很划算
Who cares? Would you grab your purse and come on? We can get a deal on it.
但我不能离开柜台啊
But I can't just leave my counter.
你到底想不想要啊
Do you want the damn doll or don't you?
-当然要  -那快点
-Of course I do. -Well, then, come on.
-慢点  -好了
-Come on. -All right.
他在那里
There he is.
好了  给她看看
Okay, show her.
这是公仔吧
Well, is it a Good Guy or not?
是的  是的
lt is. lt is.
是吧  我没骗你
Yeah, well, I told you.
多少钱
How much do you want for it?
五十块
50 bucks.
-最多10块  -30块
-10 and not a penny more. -30.
什么  你开玩笑吧  那玩意不值30块
What, are you kidding? That thing is not worth $30.
行了  不买走人  会有人买的
Enough. Take it or leave it. Somebody else will buy it.
-我买  -凯伦  这太贵了
-I'll take it. -Karen, it's too much money.
不  不贵  你不知道安迪有多想要这个公仔
No, it isn't. You have no idea how much Andy wants this doll.
但我们不知道它是不是好的
But we don't even know if the damn thing works.
给你  女士  希望它能给你和你的孩子带来快乐
Here you go, lady. May it bring you and your kid a lot of joy.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿  你等等
Hey, hold on, you!
我们怎么知道这鬼东西是不是偷的
How do we know the damn thing isn't stolen?
偷这个
Steal this.
肯定是你偷的
Steal this yourself.
玛吉
Maggie.
我想我是不是跟他约会过
I think I dated him.
快点  我们要回去工作了
Come on. We gotta get back to work.
安迪肯定会喜欢的
Andy's gonna love it!
巴克利夫人  你顺道过来真好  玩得很开心吧
Mrs. Barclay, so nice of you to drop by. Have a nice break?
对不起  克利斯威尔先生  我们只离开了一会儿
I'm sorry, Mr. Criswell. I was only gone for a minute.
通融一点吧  克利斯威尔
Have a heart, Criswell.
我们只是到楼下帮她儿子买一件生日礼物
We were just downstairs buying her little boy a birthday present.
我们可以在休息时间干这事  彼得森小姐
We have specified break times for activities like that, Miss Peterson.
毫尔太太病了  我们又缺人手
Mrs. Howe has taken sick, and we're shorthanded tonight.
你代替一下吧
You'll have to fill in for her.
不行  1小时内我得去日托中心接我儿子
I can't. I have to pick up my son at the day care center in an hour.
对不起  这是紧急情况
I'm sorry, this is an emergency.
等等  我来代替她吧
Wait a second. I'll take over for her.
彼得森小姐  你在鞋柜那边干活  而不是珠宝柜
Miss Peterson, you work in shoes, not in jewelry.
你必须做
You'll just simply have to do it.
你可以在5点离去
Now, you can take off at 5:00,
但7点时要赶回来
but you'll have to be back at 7:00.
今天我儿子生日
It's my son's birthday.
巴克利夫人  你对这份工作还满意吧
Mrs. Barclay, are you happy with your job here?
是的  我很满意
Yes, of course I am.
-那么我建议你  -嘿
-Then I suggest that... -Hey.
很扫兴  不是吗  华特
Chill out, would you, Walter?
我替你照顾安迪
I'll take care of Andy for you.
玛吉  你不能再这样做了
Maggie, you can't do it again.
别傻了  这会是几个月来最重要的约定
Don't be silly. It'll be the hottest date I've had in months.
我无法想像为啥
I can't imagine why.
嘿  你去哪里
Hey, where are you going?
公仔们要在电视上出现了
Good Guys are on TV.
我有一些更好的东西给你
Well, I may have something better for you.
什么
What?
这可不是普通的哦
This isn't groceries.
是公仔  我知道
A Good Guy! I knew it!
我知道你买了
I knew you'd get me one.
演示下它是怎么玩的
Show me how he works, okay?
嗨  我是安迪  你呢
Hi, I'm Andy. What's your name?
嗨  我是恰奇  我会是你永远的朋友  嗨
Hi, I'm Chucky, and I'm your friend to the end. Hidey-ho.
哇  它真有趣  不是吗
Wow! He's something, isn't he?
妈妈  谢谢你
Oh, Mom, thanks.
不用  宝贝
You're welcome, honey.
看  你就是这样办事的
See, that's how you build things.
晚上好  WDOL的最新插播报道
Good evening. WDOL with a late breaking report.
艾迪·卡普托  查尔斯·李·雷的帮凶
Eddie Caputo, repeated accomplice of Charles Lee Ray,
刚刚从米其干大街附近逃脱了
has just escaped the Michigan Avenue precinct.
详细情况将在9点下次播报
More details to follow on the news at 9:00 next.
嗨  恰奇  你没看我
Hey, Chucky, you're not watching me.
嗨  想玩吗
Hey, wanna play?
嘿  该上床了  安迪
Hey, it's time for bed, Andy.
不  先生  我以前从没见过这个小无赖
No, sir. Never saw the little swab before.
来吧  恰奇  我们该准备睡觉了
Come on, Chucky. We have to get ready to go to bed.
我没有逃票  古先生带我来的
I'm not a stowaway. Mr. Ghoo brought me here.
苹果先生是哪位
And who might Mr. Apple be?
玛吉阿姨  恰奇想看9点的新闻
Aunt Maggie, Chucky wants to watch the 9:00 news.
他当然想
Sure he does.
好了  孩子  走吧
Okay, kid, off we go.
快来  走吧
Come on. There we go.
恰奇
Chucky.
噢  对  恰奇
Oh, yes, Chucky.
还有你  走咯
You, too. Off we go.
现在去刷牙然后睡觉
Now, it's brush your teeth and under the covers with you.
行吗  同意吧
Okay? Agreed?
好极了
Good. Okay.
你准备好了  就大叫一声  我才可以开始
You yell when you're ready for me to tuck you in.
嗨  恰奇  想看看我的房间吗
Hey, Chucky, want to see my room?
安迪  你在刷牙吗
Andy, are you brushing your teeth?
是的  玛吉阿姨
Yes, Aunt Maggie.
好
Good.
现在是9点新闻
And now, Action News at 9:00.
今天在华盛顿
ln Washington today,
市长回复
the mayor replied
他会仔细研究国会所裁决的
that he would study the congressional findings carefully
还会考虑一些团体犯罪问题
and have the commission on gang-related violence issue recommendations to him.
交回给你  史提夫
Back to you, Steve.
谢谢  特里
Thank you, Terry.
警方已澄清了一些事实
In other news, police have now clarified the information
关于艾迪·卡普托的逃脱
regarding the escape of Eddie Caputo.
官方宣称他躲过了警方的追捕
Authorities say that Caputo managed to elude his captors
在他从监狱被送去法院的途中
while being transferred onto a prison bus on his way to court. Of course...
好  先生  关于这个你想说些什么
Okay, mister, what do you have to say about this?
说什么
About what?
来啊  来啊
Come on. Come on.
你知道吗  当我要你做啥的时候你必须听话
You know, you have to learn that when I say something, I mean it.
但我干了什么
But what did I do?
你知道我在说什么的
You know what I'm talking about.
你打开电视并把恰奇放到它前面
Turning the TV on and putting Chucky in front of it
在我说你该上床睡觉的时候
when I told you it was time to go to bed.
不是我做的
I didn't do that.
不是  那是恰奇干的咯
Oh, no? What did Chucky do?
走到起居室  自己打开电视
Walk into the living room and turn it on all by himself?
是你干的吗  恰奇
Did you do that, Chucky?
安迪  够了  现在盖上被子  快点
Andy, stop it. Now, come on, under the covers. Hurry.
但是阿姨
But, Auntie...
盖上被子  别再说话了
Under the covers and not another word.
但我并没有把恰奇放到电视机前
But I didn't put Chucky in front of the TV.
够了  行吧
Enough. Okay?
亲我一下
Give me a kiss.
晚安  宝贝  生日快乐
Good night, baby, and happy birthday.
晚安  玛吉阿姨
Good night, Aunt Maggie.
我说过如果你看新闻的话  她会抓狂的
I told you she'd be mad at you if you watched the news.
我想你  亲爱的
I missed you, my dear.
恐怕你得去参加表演了
I was afraid you weren't going to show up.
事故太严重了
Too bad about the accident.
是啊  爸爸告诉我们他们找到了
Yes. Papa told us they just found it.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我一定是从什么地方听来的
I must have heard it somewhere.
我好久没见你了  亲爱的
I haven't seen you in so long, darling.
我是说  我们能不能一起走走  或者干点别的
I mean, couldn't we take a little walk, or something?
看起来你很久没有呼吸过新鲜空气了
lt looks as though you haven't had a breath of fresh air in days.
-散步  -当然了
A walk? Of course.
外面的空气对你有好处
The air outside will do you good.
另外还可以促进你的食欲
Besides, you'll work up an appetite.
去吧
Please.
但是  珍尼丝  要下雨了
But, Janice, surely it's going to rain.
安迪
Andy?
根据有无起诉事宜
Depends on whether there's an indictment.
好吧  他们并不总是
Well, they don't always...
安迪  是你吗
Andy, is that you?
那是怎么回事
How did that happen?
呃  喂
Uh... Hello?
嗨  没事吧  安迪怎样
Hi. How's it going? How's Andy?
凯伦
Karen?
是啊  还会有谁  没事吧
Yeah. Who else would it be? ls something wrong?
呃
Uh...
没事
No.
一切都很好
Everything's fine.
你听起来不像没事的样子
Are you sure? You don't sound like everything's fine.
我只是晚上一个人有一点点焦虑不安  你明白吧
No, I just had a bit of the alone-at-night willies. You know?
现在  你就别担心了
Now, would you stop worrying
还有你能否帮我踹克里斯韦尔一脚
and give Criswell a kick in the pants for me?
没问题
You got it.
听着  玛吉  真是很感谢你
Hey, listen, Maggie. Thank you for everything.
你真是我的挚友
You're a real pal.
噢  是吗
Oh, yeah?
当然  帮我吻一下安迪
Yeah, yeah. Give Andy a kiss for me, will you?
待会见  拜
See you soon. Bye.
我究竟怎么了
What is wrong with me?
我都快给自己吓死了
I'm scaring myself half to death.
移走那路障
Step away from this barricade.
挪到后面去  没什么好看的
Come on, move it back. There's nothing to see.
把警戒线移后点
Now, let's move this police line back here.
回家吧  大家
Go on home, folks, please.
她在六楼
She was on the sixth floor.
啊  小姐  你在干什么
Miss, what do you think you're doing?
我住在这里
I live here.
安迪
Andy?
噢  不  安迪
Oh, no. Andy?
安迪
Andy?
Andy!
妈咪
Mommy!
啊  感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我太高兴了  刚才太可怕了当我
Oh, I'm so glad. I got so scared when I...
怎么了  玛吉呢
What's wrong? Where's Maggie?
她出了点了意外
She had an accident.
意外  什么意外
Accident? What kind of an accident?
巴克利太太  我是迈克·诺里斯探员  调查谋杀案的
Mrs. Barclay, I'm Detective Mike Norris, Homicide.
我能和你去外面谈谈吗
Could I talk to you out in the hall?
为什么  玛吉出什么事了
Why? What's happened to Maggie?
请告诉我
Please?
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
请看  巴克利太太
Look, Mrs. Barclay...
什么
What?
彼得森小姐死了  巴克利太太
Miss Peterson's dead, Mrs. Barclay.
什么
What?
怎么死的
How?
她从厨房的窗口摔下去了
She fell from your kitchen window.
啊  不
Oh, no.
你没事吧
You all right?
是的  我没事
Yes. All right.
过来
Come on.
噢  玛吉
Oh, Maggie.
你检查那边了吗
Did you check over here?
噢  玛吉
Oh, Maggie.
你知道这是些什么吗
You got any idea what these are?
不知道
No.
它们好像是一些脚印  是吧  很小的脚印
They look like footprints, don't they? Very small footprints.
你想暗示什么
What are you implying?
我不知道
I don't know.
安迪跑到柜子上会干些啥呢
What would Andy be doing up on the counter, right?
-什么  -另外
-What? -Besides,
我已查过他的柜子  他的鞋对不上这些脚印
I already checked his closet. None of his shoes matched these prints.
妈咪  妈咪
Mommy? Mommy?
恰奇想知道情况怎么样了
Chucky wanted to know what was going on.
安迪  我要你去睡觉
Andy, I want you to go to bed.
我和警探现在很忙
The detective and I are very busy.
但是妈妈
But, Mom...
现在  快去
Right now, please.
安迪
Andy.
你脚上是什么
What do you got on your feet?
公仔运动鞋
Good Guy PJ sneakers.
哇  过来这里
Wow. Come here.
我能看看它的底部吗
Can I see the bottoms of them?
当然可以
Sure.
看这  那是把枪  那是牛仔帽吗
Look at this. There's a gun. Is that a cowboy hat?
安迪  快上床  我马上替你盖被子
Andy, get into bed. I'll be in in a minute to tuck you in.
-但是  妈妈  -快去
-But, Mom... -Right now.
你为何这么对安迪
Why are you treating Andy like this?
他说了不知道那里为何有脚印  他就是不知道
If he says he doesn't know how those footprints got there, then he doesn't.
巴克利太太  确实有人留下脚印
Look, Mrs. Barclay, somebody made those footprints.
不是安迪会是谁
If not Andy, then who?
我不知道  而且我也不在乎
I don't know, and I don't care.
我只知道我的好朋友刚刚发生意外惨死
All I know is that I've just lost my best friend tonight to a horrible accident
我要跟儿子独处一会儿
and I would like some time alone with my son,
他和我一样伤心
who I'm sure is just as upset about this as I am.
我很抱歉  对不起
Okay. Sorry. I'm sorry.
我马上叫我的同事离开
I'll clear everybody out of here right away. Okay?
兄弟们  好了吗  走吧
Hey, guys, you done? Let's go. Chop-chop.
各位  我们要走了
Let's go, everybody. Out of here.
收队了  走吧
Let's clear this up over here. Come on.
好了
Okay.
我们走  锡德
Let's go, Sid.
你知道我的鞋为什么这么重要吗  恰奇
What do you think was so important about my sneakers, Chucky?
你也不清楚  是吧
You don't know either, do you?
如果你发现了那些脚印的任何情况  请告诉我
Well, let me know if you find out anything about those footprints.
妈咪  妈咪
Mommy, Mommy.
妈咪  我知道当时谁在厨房柜台那
Mommy, I know who was on the kitchen counter.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
-安迪  我觉得我  -谁  安迪  是谁
-Andy, I thought I... -Who, Andy? Who?
恰奇
Chucky!
你的公仔
Your doll?
今晚的故事到此结束
Andy, that's enough stories for tonight.
现在回去睡觉  听到没
Now, come on, back to bed. Now I mean it.
但是  妈妈
But, Mom...
晚安  侦探
Good night, Detective.
-又怎么了  -你在叫我吗
-What? -Are you gonna call me?
你没放弃  是吧
You don't give up, do you?
我只是  我不喜欢草草收场
I just...I hate loose ends.
我也讨厌那些不屈不挠的人
And I hate people who don't know when to stop.
哎哟
Ouch.
神勇的女士
A spirited lady.
别开玩笑
No kidding.
我明天就要
I want that autopsy report on my desk
-验尸报告  -好的
-first thing tomorrow. -Yeah.
还有你能找到的任何关于巴克利太太的信息
And anything you can find out about Mrs. Barclay and her son.
没问题  还有事吗  长官
You got it. Anything else I can do for you, sir?
噢  还有这个  这个拿到实验室去
Oh, yeah. Here. Get this to the lab.
我在厨房角落找到它的
I found it in the corner of the kitchen.
这是什么
What is this?
可能是凶器
Possible murder weapon.
不是吧
No.
得了  别开玩笑了
Come on. You're kidding me.
嘿  你在开玩笑  是吧
Hey, you are kidding me, aren't you?
因为她看见你能走路和说话
'Cause she saw you walking and talking?
我猜她无处可藏
I guess there was no hiding from her.
安迪  你在跟谁说话
Andy, who are you talking to?
恰奇
Chucky.
恰奇  啊
Chucky, huh?
是的  恰奇
Yeah, sure, Chucky.
它就坐在那里
He's sitting right over there.
恰奇还跟你说话  是吧
Chucky's been talking to you, too, hasn't he?
他说什么
What's he been saying?
什么都说
All kinds of things.
他的真名叫查尔斯·李·雷
His real name is Charles Lee Ray,
天堂里的爸爸命令它下凡来和我一起玩
and he's been sent down from heaven by Daddy to play with me.
是吗  还有其它事吗
He has, has he? Anything else?
是的  他说玛吉阿姨是婊子
Yes. He said Aunt Maggie was a real bitch
她会遭到报应的
and got what she deserved.
安迪  你怎么可以说这些可怕的事情
Andy, how can you say something so horrible?
不是我说的  是恰奇
I didn't say it. Chucky did.
安迪  够了
Andy, stop it.
你心里清楚这是你编的
You know perfectly well that you're making this up.
不  我没有  恰奇是活的  真的  他是活的
But I'm not. Chucky's alive. Really, he is.
安迪  恰奇  恰奇是个公仔
Andy, Chucky... Chucky's a doll.
他只是一些塑料和填充剂做的
He's made of plastic and stuffing.
瞧瞧它  瞧瞧它
Look at him. Look at him.
他像是其它东西吗
Now, does he look like anything else to you?
别  你会伤到他的
Don't, you'll hurt him.
安迪  看
Andy, look!
你不是真的以为恰奇是活着的吧  是吗
Now you don't really think that Chucky is alive, do you?
但他确实是
But he is.
安迪  别说了  够了
Andy, stop it. Please.
因为玛吉阿姨死了  你才这样的  是吧
It's 'cause of Aunt Maggie you're yelling at me, isn't it?
是的  我猜是的
Yes. Yes, I guess it is.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不会再编故事了
I'll stop making up stories.
谢谢
Thanks, champ.
你今晚想和我一起睡吗
Do you wanna sleep in with me tonight?
不  我没事
No, it's all right.
我有恰奇
I've got Chucky.
来  上床
Come on, into bed.
晚安  宝贝
Good night, sweetheart.
我爱你
I love you.
拜拜
Good night.
你说得对  恰奇  她不相信我
You're right, Chucky. She didn't believe me.
嗨  我喜欢被抱着
Hi. I like to be hugged.
好极了  我也喜欢
Good. I'd love to hug you, too.
嘿
Hey.
你确信昨晚没事吧
You sure you're all right about last night?
有没有发关于玛吉阿姨的恶梦
No bad dreams about Aunt Maggie?
恰奇只是个公仔  对吧
And Chucky's only a doll, right?
好了  快去学校  我爱你
All right, off to school with you, then. I love you tons.
43号街  下一站47号街
43rd street. Next stop, 47th.
那不是艾迪的吗
Is that Eddie's?
你呆在这里  我去尿尿
Look, you stay here. I have to go tinkle.
我会在这里的  恰奇
I'll be right there, Chucky.
恰奇
Chucky?
巴克利太太
Mrs. Barclay.
诺里斯探员  我刚收到你的消息就过来了
Detective Norris, I came as soon as I got your message.
你没去学校接你儿子吧
You haven't been to the school to pick up your son yet?
没有  我直接从工作的地方过来的  怎么了
No. No, I came directly from work. Why?
进我办公室说吧
Let's go into my office.
安迪出什么事了
Is something wrong with Andy?
请
Please.
我
I...
我不知道怎么说才好  巴克利太太
I don't know how to tell you this, Mrs. Barclay.
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
你知道你的玛吉阿姨为什么会从窗户那摔下去的吗
Do you have any idea why your Aunt Maggie fell out of that window?
知道
Yes.
能告诉我为什么吗
Could you tell me why?
因为她看到了恰奇  被吓坏了  然后就掉下去了
'Cause she saw Chucky, and it scared her so much, she fell out.
是吗  啊
Oh, she did, huh?
为什么恰奇要去见艾迪·卡普托呢
So why did Chucky go to see Eddie Caputo?
妈咪
Mommy!
噢  安迪
Oh, Andy.
没事  宝贝  来
All right, sweetheart. Come on.
听我说  好吗
Now listen to me, okay?
没人会相信你是恰奇干的
Nobody believes you about Chucky.
除非你现在就说真话
Unless you start telling the truth right now,
他们想把你从我身边弄走
They're going to take you away from me.
听到了没  恰奇
You hear that, Chucky?
说话吧  不然他们要把你弄走了
They're taking me away unless you say something.
求你了  说话吧
Please, say something.
快  恰奇  说啊
Come on, Chucky. Say something.
告诉我为什么你一切都骗我
Tell me why you lied to me about everything.
快  恰奇  说话呀
Come on, Chucky. Say something.
告诉我
Tell me.
嗨  我是恰奇  我会是你永远的好朋友  嗨
Hi, I'm Chucky, and I'm your friend to the end. Hidey-ho.
妈咪  他是故意的
Mommy, he's doing it on purpose.
他说过我不能泄露他的秘密  否则他会杀了我
He told me never to tell about him or he'd kill me.
巴克利太太  我是阿得莫  来自县城
Mrs. Barclay, my name is Dr. Ardmore. I'm from County General.
我见的够多了
I've seen more than enough.
也许安迪应该跟我们一起待几天
Maybe Andy should spend a couple of days with us.
说话啊  你个小混蛋
Well, say something, you little bastard.
说啊  该死
Say something, damn it!
嗨  我喜欢被人拥抱
Hi. I like to be hugged.
他想要你成为他最好的朋友
"He wants you for a best friend."
当然
Yeah, sure.
嗨  我是恰奇  想和我一起玩吗
Hi, I'm Chucky. Wanna play?
跟我说
Talk to me.
快  讲啊
Come on, talk.
我说跟我说话  该死  好吧
I said, talk to me, damn it. All right.
我会让你出声的
Then I'm gonna make you talk!
说啊  否则我把你扔到火里
I said talk to me, damn it, or else I am gonna throw you in the fire!
你这蠢婊子  你这荡妇
You stupid bitch! You filthy slut!
我会教你和我做爱
I'll teach you to fuck with me!
不  不
No! No!
住手
Stop!
不
No.
No!
噢  诺里斯探员
Oh, Detective Norris!
巴克利太太  你在这里干什么
Mrs. Barclay, what are you doing back here?
安迪说的是真话
Andy was telling the truth.
恰奇是活物  他杀死了艾迪·卡普托
Chucky is alive and he killed Eddie Caputo.
-什么  -我把他带回公寓了
-What? -I took him home to my apartment.
我想把装他的盒子扔掉
I was about to throw away the box that he came in
突然电池从里面掉出来了
when the batteries fell out.
你们还没发现吗
Don't you see?
他不用电池就可以活动还有说话
He's been moving and talking for days without any batteries in him.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在说我是如何发现这公仔是活的
How I found out the doll was alive.
我威胁把他扔到火堆里
See, I threatened to throw him into the fireplace,
突然他就活过来了
when all of a sudden, he came alive in my hand.
我扔下他  而他则跑出了房子
I dropped him, and he got up and ran out of the apartment.
晚安  巴克利太太
Good night, Mrs. Barclay.
等一下  我在告诉你事实
Wait a minute. I am telling you the truth.
他杀了玛吉  他杀了艾迪·卡普托
He killed Maggie. He killed Eddie Caputo.
听着  巴克利太太
Look, Mrs. Barclay.
我很同情你  我真的很同情
I sympathize with you. I really do.
我讨厌今天所发生的事情
I hated what happened in there today.
但是撒谎对你儿子没好处
But lying is not gonna help your son.
说谎  我像是在说谎吗
Lying? Does this look like I'm lying?
你怎么被咬的
How did you get those?
恰奇咬的
Chucky bit me.
啊  天啊
Oh, for God's sake.
好的  你不信
All right, don't believe me.
你现在去哪里
Where you going?
去找恰奇
To find Chucky.
你怎么找
How you gonna do that?
我先去找把恰奇卖给我的那个小贩
I bought him from a peddler where I work. I'll start there.
那里晚上治安很差
That isn't a good part of town to be in at this time of night.
巴克利太太  你听到了没
Mrs. Barclay, do you hear me?
在晚上这个时候你不会要去那吧
You don't want to go down there at this time of night.
该死
God damn it.
呃
Uh-huh.
她在那干嘛
What's she doing here?
嘿  打扰一下
Hey, excuse me.
先生
Mister.
我不想伤害你的  还记得我吗
I'm not gonna hurt you. Do you remember me?
不  不记得
No, no.
不好意思  我昨天向你买了一只公仔
I'm sorry. I bought a doll from you
和我朋友一起在卡尔森商店后面
in back of Carson's department store with my friend yesterday.
-公仔  -是的  公仔
-Doll? -Yes, a Good Guy doll.
你卖给我的  还记得吗
You sold it to me. Do you remember?
噢  公仔  怎么了
Oh, yeah, a doll. What about it?
你从哪里搞到的
Where did you get it?
我告诉你的话你会给我什么好处
What will you give me if I tell you?
我钱不多  有的都给你
I don't have much, but you're welcome to whatever I have.
还不够  你还有什么
It's not enough. What else you got?
就这些了
That's all I've got.
就这些
All you got?
你到底  是的
What are you... Yes.
这不是你所有身家
That's not all you got.
-等等  -不  你还有很多
-Wait a minute. -No, you got a lot.
没有  没有  没有
No. No, no.
不  等一下  不  不
No. Wait. No, no!
猪
Pig!
天哪  他是警察
Christ, he's a cop!
好吧  你们几个也想试试
All right. What about the rest of you?
你们也想来聚一聚吗
You wanna party, too?
现在可以告诉这位女士了吧
All right. Now, you want to answer the lady's question now?
你从哪里搞到那公仔的
Where did you get the doll from?
我什么都不知道
I don't know nothing about no doll.
你什么都不知道啊
You're not gonna know nothing about nothing in a minute,
快告诉我  说
unless you talk to me. Now talk!
华比区一个被烧毁了的玩具店  我在那里得到的
A burned-out toy store on Wabash. That's where I got it.
滚
Get out of here.
怎么了
What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
等等  那小贩说了些什么让你这么沮丧
Well, wait a minute. Something the peddler said upset you. What was it?
我说过了  没什么
I just told you, nothing.
见鬼了  我儿子很危险  究竟是什么
God damn it. My son's life is at stake. Now, what was it?
他说他拿到公仔的地方
The place where he said he got the doll,
查尔斯·李·雷就是死在那里的
Charles Lee Ray died there.
谁
Who?
那杀人犯和艾迪·卡普托是搭档
The Lake Shore Strangler. The man who's partners with Eddie Caputo.
嘿  你要去哪里
Hey. Where are you going now?
华比和范拜仁
Wabash and Van Buren.
那里什么都没有  那家店已经毁了
There's nothing there. It's an abandoned wreck of a store.
为什么你不相信我
Why don't you believe me?
查尔斯·李·雷死时  那里被闪电击中了
It was struck by lightning the night that Charles Lee Ray died.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因为我在那  是我杀死他的
Because I was there. I was the man who killed him.
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
你不会把这种事告诉别人的
It's not exactly the kind of thing you tell someone.
来吧  我送你回家  你需要休息
Come on, let me take you home. You need some sleep.
他说了什么吗  随便什么
Did he say anything? Anything at all?
-谁  -查尔斯·李·雷
-Who? -Charles Lee Ray.
有啊  他威胁要杀了我和艾迪·卡普托
Yeah. He threatened to kill me and Eddie Caputo.
我很抱歉你没能找到什么可以救安迪的
I'm sorry you couldn't find anything to help Andy.
真的很抱歉
I really am.
但我知道
But I did.
我发现恰奇就是查尔斯·李·雷
I found out that Chucky is Charles Lee Ray.
我唯一不知道的是他怎样进入那公仔里面去的
The only thing I don't know is how he got inside the doll.
晚安  巴克利夫人
Good night, Mrs. Barclay.
查尔斯·李·雷住哪
Where did Charles Lee Ray live?
好了  你能不能下车
Look, please, will you just get out of the car?
告诉我他住在哪里
Hey, just tell me where he lived.
你还不明白吗  安迪的性命跟这个关系很大
Don't you understand? Andy's life depends on it.
斯托岛730号  南部
730 Stoney Island, the south side.
我查过了
But I've already checked the place out.
那里什么也没有  晚安
There's nothing there. Now, good night.
等等  你要去哪里
Wait a minute. Where are you going?
-回家  休息一会  -你不能那样
-Home, to get some sleep. -No, you can't do that.
你还不明白  你刚刚说过了
Don't you see? You just said it.
恰奇杀了卡普托  你很吃惊吗
Chucky killed Caputo. That leaves you.
是的
That does it.
听我说
Oh, please listen to me.
出去
Out.
我在告诉你事实
I am telling you the truth.
为什么你不相信我
Why won't you believe me?
因为我很理智  巴克利夫人  理智而且清醒
Because I'm sane, Mrs. Barclay. Sane and rational.
好吧  好吧
All right. All right.
你还记得你遇到我的
Do you remember what you said
第一个晚上说过的话吗
the first night you met me in my apartment?
-什么  -你不喜欢悲惨的结局
-What about it? -You said you didn't like loose ends.
我已经很惨了
Well, I'm a loose end.
在查清楚这件事前你别想让我走
You can't just let go what I said tonight without checking it out.
最后一次  巴克利夫人  晚安
For the last time, Mrs. Barclay, good night.
晚安  混蛋
Good night, asshole.
啊  天
Oh, god!
小心
Jeez, look out!
嗨  麦琪
Hi, Mikey.
你这样做没用  麦琪  你伤不了我
Won't do you any good, Mikey. You can't hurt me.
凯伦
Karen.
你在那里干什么
What are you doing here?
在我昨晚跟你说过话后
After I talked to you last night,
我决定回到局里并翻阅了雷的档案
I decided to go back to the station and pull Ray's file.
我知道了一些事
I learned a couple of things.
雷的小名就叫恰奇
His nickname was Chucky,
他跟这个男人混了很久
and he spent a lot of time with this man.
我们能做的就是在恰奇之前先找到他
Now, all we have to do is find him before Chucky does.
你好  约翰
Hello, John.
这里
Over here.
嗨
Hi.
是我  恰奇
It's me. Chucky.
你怎么认为  符咒的作用吗
What do you think? The grigri work?
你知道吗  我之前来学习驱鬼的时候
You know, when I came here learning all that stuff about how to beat death,
你可能觉得我还是个小屁孩
I thought maybe you were pulling my chain.
但现在不是了  现在不一样
But not now. Not now.
只有一个问题
Only one problem.
什么
What?
就是我不认为有人能伤到我
This. I didn't think anybody could hurt me.
但昨晚我被枪击了
But last night, I got shot.
知道吗  受伤了
You know something? It hurt.
他妈的受伤了  甚至流血了
It hurt like a son of a bitch. It even bled.
为什么这样  约翰
Now why's that, John?
你正在转变为人类吧
You're turning human.
什么
What?
你寄居在身体上的时间越长
The more time you spend in that body,
你就越来越向人类转变
the more human you'll become.
你意思是我以后都得生存在这身体里
You mean I have to live out the rest of my life in this body?
没门  你把我弄到里面去  就得把我弄出来
No fucking way. You got me into this, you get me out.
我做不到  恰奇
I can't do that, Chucky.
为什么
Why not?
因为你很讨厌
Because you're an abomination,
你的暴行违背了天理
an outrage against nature.
你扭曲了我教你做的全部事情把它用于邪恶
You perverted everything I've taught you and used it for evil.
你必须被阻止
And you have to be stopped.
你知道吗  我早就想到类似这样的事情可能会发生
You know, I thought something like this might happen.
所以我已经准备好了
That's why I prepared for it.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
你自己的魔人
Your own personal mojo, doc.
给我
Give me that.
当然  你想要什么样的  断了腿的
Sure. How do you want it? Broken leg?
你就不应该告诉你的顾客这种东西藏在哪里  约翰
Shouldn't tell your customers where you hide things like this, John.
每次都让你陷入麻烦
Gets you in trouble every time.
我怎样才能离开这身子
Now how do I get out of this body?
不  我不会告诉你
No, I won't tell you.
是吗
Yeah?
告诉我或者去死  约翰  你选择
Tell me or die, John. Your choice.
不要  我会告诉你的
No, I'll tell you.
你必须把你的灵魂传出那个公仔
You have to transfer your soul out of the doll
给第一个看到你真面目的人体内
into that of the first human being you revealed your true self to.
你是说只要传给第一个知道我是活的人就行了
You mean the first person I let in on the fact that I was really alive?
我不相信  真不敢相信
I don't believe it. I just don't believe it.
第一个知道我秘密的是一个6岁的孩子
The first person I let in on my little secret was a six-year-old kid.
我又要变成一个6岁的小孩
I'm gonna be six years old again.
约翰  真有趣  但我会干
Well, John, it's been fun, but I gotta go.
我和那小孩还有约
I have a date with a six-year-old boy.
而你则和死神有约
And you have a date with death.
再见  约翰
So long, John.
别急  等等  等等
Hold it. Wait, wait.
啊  老天
Oh, my God.
-太迟了  -什么
-Too late. -What?
一定要救那小孩  一定
Must save the boy. Must...
必须把他的灵魂
Must get his soul
放进他的身体就像他进入公仔的身体里一样
into him like he got into doll.
什么
What?
你必须在他唱出圣歌前阻止他
You must stop him before he can say the chant.
在他说出来前杀了他
Kill him before he can say it.
但要怎样做  怎么做
But how? How?
心脏  他的心几乎是人类的
The heart. His heart is almost human.
这是唯一的方法  穿过心脏
It's the only way. Through the heart.
救我  救我  阿得莫医生  恰奇在这里
Help me! Help me! Dr. Ardmore, Chucky's here!
救命  他要来杀我  在这里  恰奇在这里
Help me! He's coming to kill me! He's here. Chucky's here.
我没看到有人
I don't see anybody.
但是医生  恰奇在这里
But, Doctor, Chucky's here,
他要杀我
and he's going to kill me.
恰奇在这里  他要杀我
But Chucky is here, and he's going to kill me!
他要杀我
He's going to kill me.
别丢下我  求你了
Please don't leave me. Please.
不
No!
安迪  别动
Andy, stop.
嘿  等等
Hey, wait a minute.
阻止他
Stop him!
查一下北面的走廊
Check the north corridor.
放松  放松  没事的  安迪  没事
Easy. Easy, it's all right, Andy. It's all right.
你再也不需要它了  是吗
You're not gonna need this anymore, all right?
但我要  恰奇在房里  他想要杀了我
But I do. Chucky's in the room, and he's trying to kill me.
不  安迪  没事的  我在这儿
No, Andy. It's gonna be all right. I'm here now.
我会保护你
And I'm gonna protect you.
安迪  放松  放松点
Andy. Easy, boy. Easy.
这里没人
Come on, nobody's here.
不  别这样  他也会杀了你
No, please. He'll kill you, too.
安迪  现在
Andy, now...
不  请听我说  求你了
No, please. Listen to me. Please.
这只会让你疼一会
Andy, now this is just gonna sting you for one second.
不要  不要  不要  不要
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
不要
Stop.
发生了什么事
What happened?
小姐  你能离开一会吗
Look, miss, could you just excuse us for a minute here, all right?
什么
What?
-什么  -是啊  是啊
-What? -Yeah, yeah.
把他放到那机器里面炸成薯片  但他跑了
Fried him to a crisp with the electric shock machine and then he escaped.
跑了  哪里
Escaped? Where?
我们也不知道  但我想她知道
We don't know, but I bet she does.
是恰奇  你见过恰奇吗
Chucky. You seen Chucky anywhere?
-谁是恰奇  -一个公仔
-Who's Chucky? -Kid's doll.
跟局里那个是一样的
The same one that was at the station house.
你见过他吗
Have you seen him anywhere?
我怎么会知道一个公仔  你们去哪
What am I gonna know about a doll? Where are you going?
他们认为是安迪干的
They think Andy did it.
我知道  那女孩说恰奇在这里
I know, the girl said that Chucky was here,
找安迪
and that he was looking for Andy.
-安迪能去哪呢  -家
-But where would Andy go? -He'd go home.
我说去那里如果他有麻烦的话
I always told him to go there if he was in trouble.
-他有钥匙吗  -在门毯下
-Does he have a key? -It's under the mat.
快点  快点  我们没有时间了
Come on. Come on. We don't have much time.
看  乔治
Look, George.
一些小孩把他们的公仔扔在了电梯里
Some child left their doll in the elevator.
别管它
Leave it alone.
那些扔了公仔的小孩会回来找
Whoever left it there will come back looking for it.
真丑的公仔
Ugly doll.
-靠
-Fuck you.
吃惊吧
Surprise!
打啊
Batter up!
给我力量吧  求你了
Give me the power, I beg of you.
安迪
Andy!
-安迪  -安迪
Andy! Andy!
安迪  你能听到吗
Andy, can you hear me?
安迪
Andy!
站住  噢
Stop! Ow!
安迪
Andy.
凯伦  凯伦  你没事吧
Karen, Karen, are you all right?
喔  迈克
Oh, Mike.
照顾好安迪
Just take care of Andy.
凯伦  凯伦
Karen, Karen.
拿着这个  拿着
Take this. Take it.
迈克
Mike!
妈咪
Mommy.
怎么了  卡壳
What's wrong? Gun jammed?
安迪
Andy!
安迪  救我  火柴
Andy, help me. The matches.
安迪
Andy!
求你  现在
Please! Now!
安迪  不要
Andy, no, please.
我们是永远的好朋友  记得吗
We're friends to the end. Remember?
已经结束了  朋友
This is the end, friend.
啊  宝贝
Oh, my baby.
凯伦  安迪
Karen? Andy?
你们没事吧
You all right?
安迪  帮我拿点急救包
Andy, go get me the first-aid kit
在厨房水槽下面
under the kitchen sink really fast. Okay?
怎么了
What happened?
天啊  恰奇已经死了
Oh, God. Chucky's dead.
妈咪  恰奇跑了
Mommy, Chucky's gone.
安迪  快点
Andy, hurry up.
安迪
Andy.
嗨  安迪
Hello, Andy.
妈咪
Mommy.
Mommy!
把那男孩给我  我不杀你
Give me the boy, and I'll let you live.
听到了没  把他给我
Do you hear me? Give me the boy.
妈咪
Mommy!
把小孩交给我
Give me the boy.
这里究竟发生了什么事
What the hell's going on here?
噢  嘿  嘿  嘿
Oh, hey, hey, hey.
凯伦
Karen.
天
God!
上帝
Oh, Jesus.
有警员倒下了  多处刀伤
Yeah, I got a cop down here. Multiple stab wounds.
北格兰街的部鲁斯特区  快点
The Brewster Apartments on North Grand Street. Make it fast.
他们10分钟内到  发生什么事了
All right, they're gonna be here in 10 minutes. Now, tell me what happened.
那小孩说对了  公仔是活的
The kid was right. The doll's alive.
他几乎把我们3人都困住了
He almost got the three of us.
正经点  你胡说什么啊
Come on, what are you talking about?
你不信  继续到大厅里检查下
You don't believe me? All right, well, go on. Check it out in the hall.
他可能在这厅里的任何地方
It's scattered all over the place.
但别碰它  懂吗
But don't touch it. Do you understand me?
别碰它任何地方
Don't you touch one part of it!
好的  放松点
All right, look. Take it easy, okay?
放松点  好吗
Just relax yourself, all right? All right.
迈克  我想你去看看这玩意
Okay, Mike. I'd like you to take a look at this thing, okay?
因为那东西不可能还是活的
Because there's no way this thing's alive.
我告诉你别碰
I thought I told you not to touch it.
迈克  理智点
Mike, will you be sensible?
看  就像死了一样  它死了
Come on, look. It's as dead as they come. It's dead.
杀了他  杀了他
Choke him! Kill him!
我要拧断他的脖子
I'll rip his throat out.
杀了他
Kill him!
Kill him.
杀了他  扼死他  别让他跑了
Kill him now! Strangle him! Don't let go!
-天
-God.
杀了他们  杀了他们  杀光他们
Kill them! Kill them! Kill them all!
心脏  射他的心脏
The heart. Shoot him in the heart.
嗨  我是恰奇
Hi, I'm Chucky.
想玩
Wanna play?
你现在相信我了吧
You believe me now?
嗯
Yeah.
但还有谁信我
But who's gonna believe me?
过来
Come on.
没事吧  好了没  走吧
All right. Ready? Here we go.
过来
Come on.
安迪
Andy.
走  我们和迈克一起去医院
Come on. We're gonna go to the hospital with Mike.
走吧
Let's go.